<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AustinBreslinDev</title>
    <description>Developer blog by AustinBreslinDev. Discussing and showing different aspects of programming in various programming languages. Java, C#, JavaScript, Typescript.
</description>
    <link>https://austinbreslindev.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://austinbreslindev.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 19:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 19:35:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Think about accessibility</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Why we all need to start working on accessibility now and not later? Well that is 
because we all want to deliver an excellent product for our users, we want to 
display our skills and be proud of the thing that we built. We want everyone to 
share in this experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How annoyed are you when users give you negative feedback and don’t lie about 
this. I know that feedback means that you can make your product even better and 
who doesn’t want to make a better product to learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well imagine that there are many people out there who can’t use your product as 
it stands right now, they won’t give you feedback because they are used to poor 
experiences no matter where they go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or since your a developer, I’ll assume that you are a power user with your 
keyboard, imagine if your &lt;abbr title=&quot;Integrated Development Environment&quot;&gt;
IDE&lt;/abbr&gt; didn’t have your keyboard shortcuts, think I’m wrong? Try to stop using
copy and paste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t built a website that is accessible, you have inadvertently built a 
site that is missing your own favorite features, now doesn’t this sound silly? 
This is why you need to start doing accessibility now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;For your information&quot;&gt;FYI&lt;/abbr&gt;: I am not a UX/UI Developer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is usually completely mis-represented within the web development
community. When you think of accessibility you probably go straight into 
thinking about &lt;abbr title=&quot;Accessible Rich Internet Applications&quot;&gt;ARIA&lt;/abbr&gt;, 
as if it just something that gets tacked onto your website and this will solve 
all your problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having worked in the computer industry for so long professionally, since
IE 8, I see businesses think that ARIA is the solution to an accessible web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;so-what-does-aria-achieve&quot;&gt;So what does &lt;abbr title=&quot;Accessible Rich Internet Applications&quot;&gt;ARIA&lt;/abbr&gt; achieve?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARIA is a tool to fill in the gaps between Visual and Non-Visual users. It will
not solve all accessibility problems for you because it isn’t context aware, it’s 
not AI after all. We the web &lt;abbr title=&quot;Developer&quot;&gt;dev&lt;/abbr&gt; are the only 
people/things that are context aware in the process of designing the user experience (&lt;abbr title=&quot;User Experience&quot;&gt;UX&lt;/abbr&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-an-accessible-web&quot;&gt;What is an accessible web?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My definition would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An accessible website is a website that caters for all types of users and 
provides them all a comparable experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How you achieve this is by thinking about all your users types at all times during
the &lt;abbr title=&quot;Software Development Life Cycle&quot;&gt;SDLC&lt;/abbr&gt;. Are there any tips
for this? A simple technique that I have heard from many 
&lt;abbr title=&quot;User Experience&quot;&gt;UX&lt;/abbr&gt; developers is that you should give each 
of your user types a name and characteristics. This is an analog hack to make it 
easier for you and your whole team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is getting too long, so I will follow up with a post about the personas 
that every website needs to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to convince people to change even if they know they should. This post 
was an attempt to for all of us to identify the missing features, yes features 
within our website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about accessibility is about thinking about the usability of your 
website for all of your users including yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 09:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://austinbreslindev.github.io/categories/web/accessibility/think-about-accessibility/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://austinbreslindev.github.io/categories/web/accessibility/think-about-accessibility/</guid>
        
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        <category>accessibility</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
